Akira Takezawa

Address: Sumida-ku, Tokyo, Japan – 5-6-13

Contact: (+81) 8093470238 | akiratakezawa71@gmail.com Personal website: https://samurainote.github.jo/ & Linkedin

DATA ANALYST

Profound, Insightful, and result-driven Data Analyst with sharp analytics skills and experience in the Digital Marketing field in Media and E-commerce platform business. Currently working as a Lead Data Analyst at LIFULL. Present areas with practical experiences are Time Series Modeling and Causal Inference, also Statistical Hypothesis testing. Also an alumni of Machine Learning Bootcamp 2018 winter batch from Byte Academy from NY. Excels in Data Diagnosis from Business Contexts. Outstands in defining the problem which should be focused, collaborate as a Team in English and Japanese.

AREA OF EXPERTISE:

Statistical Hypothesis testing | Time-series Modeling | State-space Modeling | Causal Inference | Anormaly Detection | Bayesian Inference | Experimental Design | Relational Database | Machine Learning | Natural Language Processing(*a bit)

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES _____

- Platforms: MacOS Mojave version 10.14.6
- Language: R, Python, Stan
- Libraries: bsts, KFAS, StatsModels, CausalImpact, Prophet, Scikit-learn, Keras, Tensorflow
- Databases: Google BigQuery, PostgreSQL
- Tools: Tableau, Github, Hadoop, Docker, JIRA, Google Analytics, Salesforce

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full-time: Lead Data Analyst / LIFULL in Tokyo, Japan, June 2019 - Current

We work as a cross section team and assign as an analytical assistant for each project in different divisions. For instance, I execute Causal Inference for TV commercial effect on multiple KPIs with Brand Marketing division. And also Statistical Hypothesis testing in RCT experimental design for a comparison of new/old UI designs with UI designer team. Especially, I built State-space Modeling, sometimes it could be a non-linear model as well, for multiple prediction tasks with Digital Advertisement Bidding automation project and anomaly detection task within the system.

Normally, we start our analytical projects from the Requirements Definition with stakeholders and end up the process with an explanation meeting for bussiness-side people by using Tableau or sometimes microsoft powerpoint slides.

Beyond individual daily tasks, I also operate weekly Data Analytist team meeting and share statistical method or new technology in data science programming for members as a knowledge sharing.

I'm quite familier with not only user access log data from digital device, user search data in website, and digital advertisement data. But also B2B clients data which supports decision making in sales activities.

Key Achievements:

- Causal Impact for TV advertisement effect: a project with Google's Data Scientists to evaluate the causal effect of TV ads
- Anomaly Detection: detect change point of advertisment cost fraud by CUSUM tecnique
- Bayesian A/B testing for UI designs: to execute and explain clearly the result of RCT without using the term "p-value"
- Dynamic Generalized Linear Modeling for Web Advertisement: we build Automatic Digital Marketing Execution System by using a predictive model and I modeled some of them in Stan by collaborating with Machine Learning Engineers
- Real estate Inquiry prediction by random forest: to identify feature importance by learning over 50,000 rooms data in Tokyo

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE - Akira Takezawa

Subcontracting: Bussiness Analyst / Xvolve Inc. in Tokyo, Japan, August 2018 - December 2018

I helped to manage all marketing metrics of the high-classes dating matching web service which is called "Bachelor" and create multiple dashboards for business team members. And also built and improved a matching algorithm by using machine learning to maximize customer satisfaction for each dating and the matching system. I executed A/B testings in the frequentist way as well and tell the marketing team if results had statistically significant difference or not.

Key Achievements:

- Built a KPI Tracking Dashboard for team members which are automatically updated once per a week
- A/B Testing: applied Statistical Hypothesis testing for the decision making of applying new UI design
- Built a Logistic Regression Modeling: for maximizing customer satisfaction and trust for the matching system

Full-time: Data Analyst / Cospa Creation Co. in Tokyo, Japan, April 2017 - July 2018

The company, which operates one of the largest online drop shipping platform in Japan which is called "通販素材.com,". I conducted Data Mining on over 2,000 our private products, mostly centering on interiors. Mixed both quantitative actual Sales Data Analysis and making hypotheses based on qualitative research on market trends or needs for the product planning team. An exciting part of job was break down physical products into Variables like function or some SEO keyword which is also an important element for the sales results.

Key Achievements:

- Scored top total sales as a Data Analysts: in the first year among other analysts who joined the company in the same year
- Built Hand-made Data Visualization Dashboard: on Microsoft excel for other Data Analysts to improve team productivity
- Introduced SEO based product sales Analysis: by using dummy variable technique and made them as a feature value

Official Certification _____

- IBM Data Science Bootcamp Certification from Jigsaw Academy in Bangalore, India
- Machine Learning / Deep Learning Bootcamp Alumni from Byte Academy in New York, US
- Toefl ibt 88

Academic Background _____

- Graduated from Machine Learning winter Bootcamp of 2018 from Byte Academy in NY
- Economics Bachelor Degree of Economics, Hokkaido University (Statistics and Econometrics as sub-mejor)
- Mohka High School: entranced and graduated as the Top student.

Data Science Activities _____

- Publishment from LIFULL Enginerr Blog: https://www.lifull.blog/entry/2019/12/25/151030
- Official Writer of Towards Data Science on Medium: https://bit.ly/357rhrF
- Write about stats here: https://giita.com/neuman71
- Machine Learning Personal Projects on GitHub: https://github.com/samurainote/portfolio
- My current working Git Account: https://github.com/neuman03